Guide to the James A. Healy Collection of Irish literature, 1870-1976
Department of Special Collections
- CATALOGUE OF MANUSCRIPT, BOXES 1-16
  - JACK B. YEATS to JAMES A. HEALY (1942-1955)[no letters for 1941] (Box 13, Folder 227)
    - Jack BY (D) to JAH, 8-24-46., ALS - 2, enc. autograph description of paintings and receipt - 4 w/cov.
    - Jack BY (D) to JAH, 11-30-46., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Jack BY (D) to [JAH], [Christmas 1946]., ANS with sketches - 1 w/cov.
    - Jack BY (D) to JAH, 2-12-48., ANS - 1 w/cov.
    - Jack BY (D) to JAH, 7-14-48., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - Jack BY (D) to JAH, 11-11-48., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Jack BY (D) to JAH, 5-21-49., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - Jack BY (D) to JAH, 1-21-50., ANS - 1 w/cov.
    - [Jack BY] (D) to [JAH, 12-6-51]., AN - 1 w/cov (printed Christmas card designed by Jack BY)
    - Jack BY ([D]) to [JAH, 1952]., Printed catalogue for Boston exhibit 1951-52, with 2 printed invitations, one annotated
    - [Jack BY] (NP) to [JAH, 1952]., Printed New Year card, designed by Jack BY, w/cov.
    - Jack BY (D) to JAH, 7-19-52., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Jack BY (D) to JAH, 9-20-53., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - [Jack BY] (NP) to [JAH, 1953]., Printed New Year card, designed by Jack BY, w/cov.
    - Jack BY (D) to JAH, 5[for 6]-10-55., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - [Jack BY] (NP) to [JAH, 1954]., Printed New Year card, designed by Jack BY, w/ AN - 1
    - [Jack BY] (NP) to [JAH, 12-17-55]., Printed Christmas card, designed by Jack BY, w/ AN - 1, w/cov.
    - [Jack BY] (NP) [to JAH?] [1954]., 2 printed cards, left blank
  - JACK B. YEATS to JOHN CALDWELL MYERS (Box 14, Folder 228)
    - Jack BY (D) to John Caldwell Myers, 7-10-39., ALS - 1 w/cov.
  - JACK B. YEATS to ANNA and ELIZABETH RUSSELL (Box 14, Folder 229)
    [this folder contains Xerox copies only; originals are in the Library of the National Art Gallery, Dublin]
    - Jack BY (D) to [Anna] Russell, 5-16-32., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 12-15-38., Pc of ANS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY and M. C. Yeats (NP) [to AR], ND., Pc of 2 picture postcards w/ ANSs - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 3-1-39., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - [Jack BY] (D) [to AR, 1939].Pc of Abbey Experimental Theatre Programme for first production of Jack BY's Harlequin's Positions, PD - 4 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 4-10-40., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 12-1?-40., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 5-14-41., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, [early 1940's?]., Pc of Christmas card w/ ANS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, [mid-1940's?]., Pc of Christmas card w/ ANS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 6-29-46., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 6-7-47., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, [Christmas] 1947., Pc of ANS w/ sketches - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 12-27-47., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 4-26-47., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 6-26-48., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 12-21-49., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR and Elizabeth Russell, Christmas [1949?]., Pc of card w/ ANS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 7-8-50., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 7-12-50., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 7-18-50., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 7-31-50., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 8-6-50., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 9-19-50., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 12-22-50., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 1?-8-51., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 5-9-51., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 7-31-51., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 8-11-51., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 9-5-51., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 11-17-51., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, Christmas [1951?]., Pc of AN - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 1-19-52., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 2-7-52., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 7-16-52., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 1952., Pc of AN on exhibit invitation card - 1
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 1-6-52., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 6-16-53., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 12-29-53., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 4-7-54., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 5-11-54., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 10-18-54., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 10-29-54., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 10-12-55., Pc of ALS - 2 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 7-26-56., Pc of ALS - 2 (2), enc. pc of circular for Irish Illustrated w/a, TLS - 1 (2)
    - [for Jack BY] Thomas McGreevy (D) to AR, 8-30-56., Pc of TLS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 9-4-56., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, ?-22-[56]., Pc of ANS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY (D) to AR, 3-2-57., Pc of ALS - 1 (2)
    - Jack BY and M. C. Yeats (NP)., Pc of Christmas card, signed -1 (2)
    - Jack BY (NP) to [AR], ND., Pc of CP card of Douglas Hyde's Though riders w/ ANS - 2 (2)
  - JACK B. YEATS to LILY YEATS; and UNIDENTIFIED RECIPIENT (Box 14, Folder 230)
    - Yeats, Jack (Strete) to LY, 5-16-10., ALS - 1 [fragment]; on verso is pen drawing of horse and rider
    - Jack BY (NP) to [?], ND., Handwritten compliment slip w/ ANS - 1
  - JACK B. YEATS: REPRODUCTIONS OF HIS PAINTINGS, PRINTS, ETC. (Box 14, Folder 231)
    - [Jack BY] [1913?],flyer for A Broadside, Sixth Year., PD - 4
    - [Jack BY], ND,handcolored print of cart dashing through gate in early style -, 1
    - Jack BY, ND,printed drawing of The Country Jockey on page from The London Mercury -, 1
    - Jack BY, ND, Scene at an Irish Fair, magazine clipping - 1
    - Jack BY, The Fair Day: Evening. Wexford, on page 77 from The London Mercury, May 1923-, 1
    - Jack BY, The Dark Man, photograph of oil painting -, 1
    - Jack BY, On Capel Street, Dublin, photograph mounted on a backing sheet signed by Jack BY
    - Jack BY, A Summer Evening, Rosses Point, Sligo, photograph mounted on a backing sheet signed by Jack BY
    - Jack BY, Bonfire Night, specimen printed page - 1
    - Jack BY, The June Fair, clipping - 1
    - Jack BY, The Country Shop, clipping - 1
    - Jack BY, The Tinker's Curse, clipping - 1
  - JACK B. YEATS: EXHIBIT CATALOGUES (Box 14, Folder 232)
    - Irish Paintings by Jack B. Yeats, printed list of paintings at Ferargil Galleries, NCY, 1932-, 1
    - Exhibition of Irish Paintings, promotional pamphlet, 1953-, 1
    - [Re Jack BY and others], Contemporary Irish Painting March 3-22, 1947,catalogue for Associated American Artists Galleries, NYC - 8
    - Exhibition of Paintings by Jack B. Yeats, catalogue for Saidenberg Gallery Exhibit, NYC, Jan. 19-March 1, 1953 -, 2, w/ clipping of review of exhibit
    - Jack B. Yeats, catalogue for Willard Gallery exhibit of oils, March 1962 -, 10 (2)
    - Jack B. Yeats. Irlanda, catalogue for XXXI Esposizione Biennale Internazionale d'Arte at Venice, 1962,intro. by Thomas MacGreevy -, 14
    - Jack Butler Yeats, 1871-1957, catalogue for Hayden Gallery exhibit at M.I.T., Jan.-Feb. [1965] -, 32
    - [Re Jack BY and others], catalogue leaflet Exhibition of Irish Paintings at Mrs. Cornelius J. Sullivan, NYC, ND -, 1 (2)
  - JACK B. YEATS: CLIPPING ETC. ABOUT (Box 14, Folder 233)
    - Ca. 50 clippings [a partial listing is on cards in folder]
    - Jack B. Yeats.
      See also oversize miscellanea in Vertical File; PHOTOS FROM SLIGO MUSEUM folder
  - JOHN BUTLER YEATS to MRS. SIMEON FORD (Box 14, Folder 234)
    [The undated letters have been left where they were found, rather than placing them at the end of this folder, as this is the best indication of their dates]
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, ND., ALS w/ sketch - 4 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 12-23-08., ALS w/ sketch - 2 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 8-1-10?, ALS - 4 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 1-6-11., ALS w/ sketch - 2 (2) and 2 partial trans.
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 1-14-11., ALS - 1 (2) and trans.
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 1-17-11., ALS - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NP) to Mrs. Ford, ND., ALS - 3 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, ND, I was sorry to hear..., ALS - 3 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 2-3-11., ALS w/ sketch - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, Sunday, I have just received..., ALS - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NP) to Mrs. Ford, ND, I was just about to write..., ALS - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 7-12-11., ALS - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 12-23-12., ALS - 2 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 7-23-14., ALS - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 11-6-15., ALS - 1 w/cov. (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 8-9-16., ALS - 2 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 11-21-16., ALS w/ sketch - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 11-28-16., ALS - 1 w/cov. (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 3-18-18., ALS w/sketch - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 1-8-19., ALS - 1 (2), and trans.
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 5-1-19., ALS - 2 w/cov. (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 4-27-20., ANS - 1 w/cov. (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 1-21-20., ALS - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 5-17-20., ALS w/ sketch - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, 6-25-20., ALS w/ sketch - 1 w/cov. (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to Mrs. Ford, Friday, 1920., ALS - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NP) [to Mrs. Ford], ND.Ticket for lecture, 12-14-?, PD - 1
  - JOHN BUTLER YEATS TO F. A. KING (Box 14, Folder 235)
    [Undated letters have been left where they were found in this folder, too]
    - [JBY (NP) to F. A. King], ND.Pencil sketch of woman's head -, 1
    - JBY (NYC) to F. A. King, 6-8-00., ALS w/ sketch - 2 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to F. A. King, Monday morning., ALS - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to F. A. King, Tuesday?-1-0?, ALS w/ sketch - 2 (2), and trans.
    - JBY (NYC) to F. A. King, 7-9-08., ALS - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to F. A. King, 12-10-08., ALS w/ sketch - 1 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to F. A. King, 6-2-10., ALS w/ 2 sketches - 2 (2)
    - JBY (NYC) to F. A. King, [7-20-11]., ALS - 2 (2)
  - JOHN BUTLER YEATS to AE (Box 14, Folder 236)
    - Envelope, empty, from [?] to George Russell, readdressed by JBY with addition of sketch on back -, 2 (3)
  - JOHN BUTLER YEATS: ARTICLES BY AND ABOUT (Box 14, Folder 237)
    - JBY (NYC), clipping of article The Independence of the Artist, [ Irish Statesman?], Dec. 1919., PDS - 1
    - JBY (NYC), clipping of article The Poet's Solitude, [ Irish Statesman?], March 1920., PDS - 1
    - [Re JBY]. Obituary poem for, by Jeanne R. Foster. Pc of clipping, 2-6-22., PDS - 1 (3)
    - Ca. 10 clippings about
  - LILY YEATS (Box 14, Folder 238)
    - LY (Dm) to M. Bourgeois, 8-11-13., ALS - 1
    - LY (Dm) to M. Bourgeois, [8-16-13]., APCS - 2
    - LY (Dm) to JAH, 4-5-38., ALS - 3 and trans.
    - LY (Dm) to JAH, 5-11-38., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - LY (Dm) to JAH, 6-6-38., ALS - 4 w/cov.
    - LY (Dm) to JAH, 9-6-38., ALS - 2 w/cov., and partial trans.
    - LY (Dm) to JAH, 10-17-38(first letter)., ALS - 2
    - LY (Dm) to JAH, 10-17-38(second letter)., ALS - 3, and sketch of Innisfree on separate sheet - 1. Partial trans.
    - LY (Dm) to JAH, 12-4-38., ALS - 10 w/cov., and trans. (2)
    - LY (Dm) to JAH, 12-5-38., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - LY (Dm) TO JAH, 12-22-38., APCS - 2 w/cov. [design: W. B. Yeats (when a Boy) by J. B. Yeats R.H.A.]
    - LY (Dm) to JAH, various dates in 1939., 5 empty covers from book packages - AD - 5
    - LY (Dm) to JAH, 1-17-39., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - LY (Dm) to F. A. King, 1-3-10., ALS - 6
    - LY (Dm) to F. A. King, 8-15-10., ALS - 5
    - LY (Dm) to F. A. King, 5-28-10., ALS 3
    - LY (Dm) to F. A. King, Sunday., ALS - 2
    - LY (Dm) to James J. O'Brien., Trans: TL - 1 (2)
    - LY (NP), needlepoint, St. Brendan, designed by Bridget O'Brien and worked by LY., Photograph - 1
    - LY (NP), needlepoint, Dublin Custom House, designed by Dorothy Blackham and worked by LY., Photograph - 1
    - LY (NP), needlepoint, Tobias and the Angel, designed by Bridget O'Brien and worked by LY., Photograph - 1
    - LY (NP), needlepoint, Innisfree, designed by Diana Murphy and worked by LY., Photograph - 1
    - LY (NP), needlepoint, Innisfree., Clipping of photograph - 1
  - MARY COTTENHAM YEATS (Box 14, Folder 239)
    - MCY (D) to AR, 8-6-46., Pc of ALS - 1
  - WILLIAM BUTLER YEATS (Box 15, Folder 240)
    - WBY (L) to M. Bourgeois, 4-27-?, ALS - 2
    - WBY (NP) to EAB, 1-20-15., Trans: TL - 1 (annotated by JAH; Body of letter by Ezra Pound)
    - WBY (L) to EAB, [Feb. 1915]., Trans: TL - 1
    - WBY (NP) to EAB, 9-26-[15]., Trans: TL - 1
    - WBY (Coole Park) to EAB, 5-12-[17]., Trans: TL - 1
    - WBY (Oxford) to EAB, 1-24-18., Trans: TL - 1
    - WBY (NP) to EAB, 1-5-?, Trans: TL - 1
    - WBY (NP) to EAB, 3-21-?, Trans: TL - 1
    - WBY (NP) to EAB, 4-15-?, Trans: TL - 1
    - WBY (Coole Park) to EAB, 5-4-?, Trans: TL - 1
    - WBY (R) to OG, ND., TLS - 1
    - WBY (NP), fragment, possibly to LG in 1912, Tell Bourgeois..., AL - 1 and trans.
    - WBY (R) to JAH, 9-7-[37]., ALS - 1 w/cov., and trans.
    - WBY (R) to JAH, [1937-38]., TN/ANS, enclosing A Speech... [q.v. in Section II]
    - WBY (R) to Eugene Kinkead, 7-4-[38]., Trans: TL - 1
    - WBY (L) to AE, 4-17-1?]., ANS - 2, and 2 trans.
    - WBY (NP) to?, 1-5-?, Trans: TL - 1
    - [WBY], printed invitation to meet, from O'Neills to RC, 12-16-?
    - WBY, poem, The Three Monuments, ND., Trans: TD - 1 w/cov.
  - WILLIAM BUTLER YEATS: CLIPPINGS, AUCTION NOTICES, ETC. (Box 15, Folder 241)
    - Ca. 20 auction notices
    - WBY, lecture in Cleveland, reported in Cleveland Plain Dealer, 4-29-20., Trans: TD - 1
    - [Re WBY] Review by OG of Joseph Hone's WBY from Gazette, Montreal, 4-24-43
  - WILLIAM BUTLER YEATS, AMERICAN TESTIMONIAL COMMITTEE FOR: ACCEPTANCES (Box 15, Folder 242)
    - [Eugene Kinkead], Treasurer (NP) to WBY, 6-22-38., TLc - 1
    - Ca. 60 letters, 1937-38,mainly between JAH and Kinkead, not individually listed
  - WILLIAM BUTLER YEATS, AMERICAN TESTIMONIAL COMMITTEE FOR: DECLINATIONS (Box 15, Folder 243)
    - Ca. 30 letters, 1937,not listed individually
  - WILLIAM BUTLER YEATS, AMERICAN TESTIMONIAL COMMITTEE FOR: LIST OF NAMES SOLICITED (Box 15, Folder 244)
    - Ca. 40 letters and lists, 1937-38,not listed individually
  - YOUNG, ELLA; YOUNG, HUGH; YOUNG, MABEL (MRS. PAUL HENRY) (Box 15, Folder 245)
    - Young, Ella (San Francisco) to [Joseph Campbell], 10-21-26., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - Young, Ella, poem, The Rose., ADS - 1
    - Young, Ella, poem, The Winds., ADS - 1
    - Young, Hugh H. (Baltimore) to OG, 5-15-43., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - Young, Mabel (Mrs. Paul Henry), catalogue of paintings of, 1938., PD - 3
    - Young, Mabel, clipping re -, 1
  - ZIMAND, SAVEL (Box 15, Folder 246)
    - Zimand, Savel (NYC) to AE, 1-25-28., ALS - 1
  - UNIDENTIFIED (Box 15, Folder 247)
    - [Illegible: T.S. Ivers? Wells?] (NP) to [F.A.?] King, 12-6-16., ALS - 2
    - [?], draft of open letter soliciiting American funds for Irish Statesman., TL w/a - 3
    - [UNK], 7 pp
  - PHOTOGRAPHS SENT BY ELIZABETH C. YEATS TO JAMES A. HEALY, [1938 or 1939] (Box 15, Folder 248)
    248-252: see Dept. Photograph File All annotated on verso by ECY:
    Portrait of ECY at Baggot Street office
    First Cuala Cottage, 1908, at Churchtown, Dundrum. ECY in doorway
    ECY in doorway of Gurteen Dhas, Dundrum, 1908(?0
    2 of LY's Stations of the Cross
    E. C. Yeats [at Tara] 1938
    Duplicate, annotated Elizabeth C. Yeats as we were going down the road from Tara August of 1938
    Professor John MacNeill at Tara
    Lennox Robinson at Tara
    Lennox Robinson and Mr. Frazer at Tara
    Sittingroom at Dundrum
    Another view, annotated Pencil portrait of me as a girl...
    Another view [no annotation]
    View of stove
    ECY and Anne Yeats 1935
    WBY and Jack BY at Dundrum, 1932
    WBY and Jack BY, at our gate summer 1934 or 1936?
    ECY on beach, 1937
    2 Stations of the Cross
    View from hall door [as a postcard] # 20-23 annotated by LY on verso:
    One of the stations
    St. Columcille (designed by Jack BY) and Immaculate Conception designed by MCY [on postcard]
    LY in garden [probably 1930's]
    Portrait of LY by JBY
    St. Brendan etc., embroidered by LY, and prints on table at Baggot St. (annotated by ECY and LY) #s 25-27 are not annotated:
    Station 3
    Station 11
    Station 13
    Station 14 (annotated in another hand) #s 29-40 annotated by ECY:
    Girls at tea 1908 or 1910...
    A group at tea 1908 to 1910...
    Miss Gill and Miss Ryan, 1908
    Miss Gill and Miss Ryan, Baggot Street
    Esther Ryan at the press, Baggot Street
    Esther Ryan printing a Xmas card, Baggot Street
    Miss M. Gill
    Molly Gill at press, Baggot Street
    Miss Ryan hand-colouring cards
    Corner of workroom
    Showtable in workroom
    Corner of printing room, Baggot Street
  - PHOTOGRAPHS AND PORTRAITS (Box 15, Folder 249)
    - Aldington, Richard, photograph by Blackstone. Clipping from N.Y. Herald Tribune, 9-24-39
    - Barry, Richard, photograph of, August 1946
    - Boyd, E.A., newspaper photograph [ N.Y. Times, ca. 1928?],with pencil sketch of AE reproduced beside it
    - Campbell, Richard, photograph of, ND., 4 1/2 x 6 1/2
    - Campbell, Richard, snapshot mounted on black paper (his back to camera), ND
    - Emmet, Robert, 1802.Collotype from sketch in National Library of Ireland
    - Gogarty, O. St. J., inscribed to JAH, photograph reproduced on flyer for his lectures, ND.Duplicate, not inscribed
    - Gogarty, O. St. J., 3 photos with JAH at Yarmouth, Maine, 1941., 4 x 6 1/2
    - Gogarty, O. St. J., 3 photos of Dublin with holograph annotations:
      The cul de sac of Ely Place where in the second last house -- 2 windows wide -- lived George Moore. My house with garden beyond, right. O. St. J. G.
      15 Ely Place Dublin
      The River Liffey running through Dublin -- Omit motor cars and emphasize distant dome
    - Gonne, Maud, 1900. Photograph reproduced in AIHS's The Recorder (vol. 10, no. 2), 7-1-39,p. 22
    - Gregory, Lady Isabella Augusta. Photograph by Alice Bougtuon, ND., 5 1/2 x 8
    - Henry, Paul, ND.Irish Times photograph, beside one of his paintings., 9 1/2 x 7 1/2"
    - Monahan, Michael, ND.Photograph w/a: I'm all Boy - 58., 4 x 5 1/2"
    - Moore, George, w/a October 13th 1919. Mounted photograph of oil painting, artist illegible
    - O'Casey, Sean. Photograph by Ben Pinchot reproduced for frontispiece of Theatre Arts Monthly, November 1934
    - O'Connor, Frank, ND.Reproduction of photograph., 1 1/2 x 2 1/2"
    - O'Sullivan, Seamus, see AE
    - Robinson, Lennox, ND., Photograph, 8 x 10"
    - AE. Matted selfportrait in pencil as a young man, signed., 7 x 10"
    - AE. Reproduction of pencil portrait as a young man., Clipping
    - AE. Clipping of half-length portrait by JBY, ND
    - AE. Reproduction of pencil portrait as a young man by JBY., 8 1/2 x 11"
    - AE. Pen and ink cartoon by Beatrix Duncan, ND., 8 1/2 x 11"
    - AE. Photograph by Pirie Macdonald, (NYC), ND.Inscribed For Dick Campbell who was a brother to me George Russell AE., 6 x 9"
    - AE and RC, seated on steps, ND.JAH's annotation: at home of J. St. John Gaffney, Summit, N.J., 3 copies: 5 x 6", 5 x 7", 7 1/2 x 9 1/2", and negative
    - AE. 4 snapshots, alone and with groups, mounted on black paper, ND
    - AE. Negative, ND., 7 x 9"
    - AE's cottage in Donegal [1930?].Snapshot showing [Irene Haugh?]., 4 x 2 1/2"
    - AE's cottage; owner Janey Stewart and Irene Haugh in foreground, 1930, w/cov. from IH to JAH, 2-13-62
    - AE and Seamus O'Sullivan. Snapshot in the garden at Grange House 1932., 2 x 3"
    - AE. Photograph, seated in wooden shelter, w/a from Ernest Boyd 9-27-42., 4 1/2 x 6"
    - AE. Photograph of marble bust., 2 x 3"
    - AE. Reproduction of etching by A. Hugh Fisher., 7 x 10"
    - AE. 4 newsclippings of photographs
    - AE. See also Boyd photograph above; and AE Vertical File for a few reproductions in clippings of articles about
    - Spingarn, J.E. Photograph inscribed To Ernest Boyd from his friend J. E. Spingarn 1923, 3 1/2 x 5 1/2"
    - Yeats, Elizabeth C, 1938.2 copies of photograph by Chancellor of Dublin, one inscribed To James A. Healy with kind regards from Elizabeth C. Yeats May 20, 1938
    - Yeats, Jack B. Photograph of Mrs. Seamus O'Sullivan looking at her painting of him, ND., 8 x 10"
    - Yeats, Jack B. Clipping of photograph, 1947., 2 x 3"
    - Yeats, John B. Reproduction of a selfportrait, ND., 5 x 7 1/2"
    - [Yeats, John B.] 2 snapshots of his grave at Chestertown, N.Y., 1941., 2 1/2 x 4 1/2"
    - Yeats, Lily. Reproduction of portrait by JBY called The Coral Necklace [original in National Gallery of Ireland]., 9 1/2 x 11 1/2"
    - Yeats, Lily. Clipping of photograph, ND
    - Yeats, Susan. Reproduction of drawing by JBY, 1867., 5 x 7 1/2"
    - Yeats, William B. as a boy. Postcard reproduction of portrait by JBY [originally enclosed by ECY in letter to JAH of 4-3-39.Same as card sent by LY to JAH, 12-22-38]
    - Yeats, William B. Photograph of pastel portrait by Sean O'Sullivan, 1933(original in Sligo Museum)., 8 x 10"
    - Yeats, William B. Reproduction of photograph on flyer for lecture at Carnegie Hall, 1-3-04., 8 1/2 x 11"
      [The next three are in an Oversize box:]
    - Yeats, William B. Photograph by London photographer, name illegible
    - Yeats, William B. Reproduction of portrait by Augustus John in Sir John Rothenstein's The Masters series
    - Yeats, William B. Photograph by Steichen, reproduced in tearsheet from magazine, Jan. 1933
    - Yeats, W.B. at Sorrento cottage Aug. 1930Unknown priest. Reproduction of photograph of, ND, Photograph, 5 x 3 1/2"
  - PHOTOGRAPHS: ABBEY THEATRE COMPANY (Box 15, Folder 250)
    - Carolan, P. J. Photograph, ND., 8 x 10"
    - Craig, May. Photograph, ND., 8 x 10"
    - Crome, Eileen, Photograph, ND., 8 x 10"
    - Curling, Kitty. Photograph, ND., 8 x 10"
    - Digges, Dudley. Photograph by Lucas & Pritchard, ND., 5 x 8"
    - Dolan, Michael and F. J. McCormick. Photograph, 10-23-37., 8 x 10"
    - Fitzgerald, Barry. Photograph, ND., 8 x 10"
    - Fitzgerald, Barry and F. J. McCormick. Photograph, ND., 8 x 10"
    - McCormick, F. J. as a young man. Photograph, ND., 8 x 10"
    - McCormick, F. J., as an old tramp. Photograph, ND., 8 x 10"
    - Shields, Arthur. 2 photographs, ND., 8 x 10"
    - Ernest Blythe, Pictures from a Theatre, booklet - 20. Sligo: Champion [after 1961]
  - PHOTOGRAPHS AND REPRODUCTIONS FROM SLIGO MUSEUM [arranged by artist., All 6 1/2 x 8 1/2" except where indicated] (Box 15, Folder 251)
    - Niland, Nora (Sligo), covering letter describing photographs [to JAH], 9-22-65., TLS w/a - 2
    - Clipping re Healy Collection at Sligo. Pc from Sligo Champion, 8-25-67
    - O'Connor, Frank, delivering oration at WBY's grave, 6-13-65, (2)
    - Yeats, Michael and Anne at WBY's grave, 6-13-65., (2)
    - Yeats, Michael, at presentation of WBY's Nobel Medal to Sligo Museum [ca. 1965], (2)
    - [WBY] 2 views of Nobel Medal, 4 x 6 1/2" (2 copies of each)
    - Mayer, Lady Dorothy and Nora Niland, 8-18-65
    - O'Sullivan, Mrs., looking at her portrait of Jack BY, 9-22-62
    - AE, portrait photograph of; matt of original one is inscribed For Ernest with great affection George Russell `AE8., Photograph (1)
    - AE, painting of paddlers., Photograph (1)
    - AE, painting of WBY when young., Photograph (1)
    - [AE], painting of woman with basket., Photograph (1)
    - [AE], painting of seated figures under a tree., Photograph (1)
    - [AE], painting of woman and children in woods., Photograph (1)
    - [AE], painting of satyrs and nymphs., Photograph (1)
    - AE, chalk profile of a young woman., Photograph (1)
    - AE, profile of middleaged woman with bobbed hair., Photograph (1)
    - AE, anotherprofile of same woman., Photograph (1)
    - AE, three-quarter profile of young woman., Photograph (1)
    - AE, chalk sketch of young woman with long hair., Photograph (1)
    - Jack BY, painting of man on headland., Photograph